Good morning, you're watching "DeProgram" with Ted Rall and John Kiriakou. It's Thursday, November 20th, 2025. Thank you for joining us, and good morning, John.Good morning, Ted. How you doing?I'm doing good. A little cold where I am, but that's what it's supposed to be in mid-to-late November. So.Yeah, you know, I always look for CIA-related news for us, for obvious reasons. And today there was more than usual. There was more than usual yesterday. I don't know. There's something in the air. So lots going on. I know you may have a few mild opinions about Ambassador Huckabee's meeting with the proud American patriot Jonathan Pollard. That's a crazy story. Huckabee should be fired right now. Right now. We will talk about that, obviously.You know, whenever I see "CIA cover-up in JFK assassination," I always think conspiracy [ __ ]. Today, though, this is a mainstream story. This is in Politico. It's in Axios. A former CIA historian is stepping forward as a whistleblower. It's really interesting. So about—basically, there's still stuff coming out from this thing that happened basically a couple of months after I was born, and I was born in 1963. So we'll get into that.Donald Trump is meeting with his new bestie, Zohran Mamdani. I know, it's crazy. At the Oval Office. And whatever else y'all want to talk about in the Rumble and YouTube live chats if you're watching live. You can go ahead and type that in, and we—producer Robby West—will post it up to us, and we'll answer your questions as much as we can. We are here Monday through Friday, 9 a.m. Eastern Time. And so, please like, follow, and share the show. We really need and really appreciate your generous support in all respects for the show, including but not exclusively financially.And so, John, what would you like to—I have a feeling you might like to talk about the ambassador.I could feel like exploding about Huckabee. It turns out that last July, Ambassador to Israel—former Governor of Arkansas Mike Huckabee—and the Deputy Chief of Mission met with convicted spy Jonathan Pollard.Now, Jonathan Pollard was convicted in the 1980s—1985, I believe it was—convicted of spying for Israel and sentenced to life in prison, thirty years. It was the minimum that he had to do. He served the thirty years. And I should add, all the years that I was at the CIA, every single time an Israeli prime minister would come to meet with the president, they would ask us to bomb Iran and to release Pollard. And every single time, whoever happened to be president said no. Pollard was finally released—what?—ten years ago now.That's right. He was immediately granted Israeli citizenship, flown back to Israel on an Israeli military plane, greeted as a hero—greeted as a hero by Benjamin Netanyahu at the airport—and instantly bestowed with Israeli citizenship.Now he has the balls, the unmitigated gall, to run for the Knesset in the next election as an independent but associated with the extreme right wing of Israeli politics. Wants to annex the occupied territories.Now we already know—all of us know—that Mike Huckabee is so far to the right that he's actually fallen off the edge. He's an evangelical lunatic. He has no business being in any governmental position, but he was an early endorser of Donald Trump. And because he's an evangelical and wants all the Jews to return to Israel so that Jesus can come back and the Rapture can happen—which never appears anywhere in the Bible, by the way.True.And doesn't seem like a good deal for the Jews, by the way.Yeah, it doesn't. 'Cause it's the end of the world.Exactly. They're just the linchpin. It's like they're the red shirts in this "Star Trek" episode. This clown has got to go.He won't say—and I should add—they kept the Pollard meeting off the embassy's calendar. So only now are people finding out about it, and only because somebody called the New York Times and told them. And then the New York Times was able to confirm it with two other people inside the embassy. They interviewed Pollard, and he said, yeah, I met with Huckabee. I'm not going to tell you what we talked about. Huckabee has to resign today.So I want to be really clear here. He should resign because of the breach of protocol. He should resign because of the kowtowing to a traitor. All of the above?Yes. Yes to all of those. Yes.And another thing too—the Post and the Times are reporting today, and I think this is quite important—that the White House had no idea that this meeting took place and that they're apoplectic that it took place. When—listen—I've worked in embassies for half my adult life. When an ambassador is meeting with somebody who is controversial, they have to cable the Secretary of State to ask permission. Huckabee did not. He did not do that.What was Huckabee thinking? Why did he think—I mean, Donald Trump does not strike anyone as the kind of person that you do this to.No. I mean, you wouldn't like it if you were president. I wouldn't like it either. Is he going to survive this?You know what? I think he will survive it only because Donald Trump seems to like the guy. But no other ambassador—he must worry about looking weak too, right? So it'll be kind of a tacit admission if he fires Huckabee that Huckabee pulled the wool over his eyes. Unless Trump calls him and says, Mike, you've got to resign. This is unacceptable.And again, both the Post and the Times report that Pollard called Trump a madman who has literally sold us down the drain for Saudi gold.Takes one madman to know one.I mean, Jonathan Pollard—I remember that very, very vividly. Anyone who's old enough, let's say over fifty, remembers that very well. And he really made the strongest case against dual citizenship of any human being.And just so people remember—I'm going to turn this light off real quick—just so people remember what it was that Pollard did: Pollard sold top-secret military cables and NSA intercepts to the Israelis—sold it, right, for money. The Israelis then traded that top-secret information to the Soviet Union in exchange for Soviet Jews being allowed to settle in Israel. Pollard did it for the money. He was a traitor for money. This was not—you know, this was not a Kim Philby situation.Absolutely not.Okay. I mean, look, I think it's disgusting too. I hope the president does the right thing. I have doubts, to say the least.We have some questions. Let's get to them.Effy, thanks for the dollar. What do you make of the military Egyptian planes following Erika Kirk, as reported by Candace?You know, I checked that out. I don't think it ever happened. Candace is literally the only person on Earth who's reporting this. It's picked up by the Times of India and the Hindustan Times, and it's got a life of its own around social media, but I just don't think this happened.Yeah, that was my take as well. Wouldn't be the first time that her quote-unquote reporting is less than waterproof.Three Birds, One Stone on Rumble asks: Maybe we should start the show—although a little late—with how the Israelis killed more than 100 Palestinians last night and improvised explosive devices exploded 124 buildings in Gaza in a single day. What a ceasefire they're keeping.This is very scandalous. I'm glad that you brought that up. I mean, it's absolutely disgusting. Here's the thing, right? You pointed this out months ago: the Israelis have a longstanding practice of blowing up every ceasefire that they ever agreed to. They got dragged into this one kicking and screaming by President Trump. And obviously they're trying to screw it up every way that they possibly can.Trump is kind of in a really difficult position, right? Because if he calls up Netanyahu and yells at him about this, then he risks B.B. saying, okay, fine, [ __ ] you, back to war—which is exactly what Netanyahu wants for a variety of reasons that we've discussed here a billion times. But if he doesn't do it, he comes off as a puss, which is not good either. I don't know what I would do in this situation. I think I would be starting to look at threatening them with cutting off aid.That's what George H.W. Bush did.And you have to be serious about it. That's the only thing that gets their attention, right?That's it. That's it. And he didn't even cut off aid. George H.W. Bush temporarily suspended loan guarantees for new Israeli settlements in the West Bank.Yeah, that doesn't seem like such a big deal. Okay.F.U.S.O., thanks for the extra dollar. Has the CIA ever assassinated their own agents or officers like they're some kind of cartel or prison gang?Not that that's ever been reported. I don't know. Pre-1975 was the bad old days. I honestly can't say no, but I don't know of any such incidents.Yeah, I don't remember reading any allegations to that effect. It seems—wouldn't you say that seems a little bit—I think it's unlikely.Yeah, I would call it unlikely.John, this is from AliWhy3T: John, you mentioned on Julian Dorey your first boss who wrote books on the history of political relations of countries, but I couldn't find his name. Maybe I missed it. Could you let us know his name?Yep. That was Bruce Riedel. Bruce was one of the best bosses I ever had. And in his retirement, he's been absolutely prolific in his book production. It's incredible.Another dollar from FUSO. FUSO keeps dropping the George Washingtons. If you were to be a corrupt spy—or "soccer to weigh," depending—if you were to be a corrupt spy, would you rather be recruited by a hot Chinese spy or a hot Russian spy?Oh, geez, man. What a totally loaded question. I'd have to say Russian for me.Yeah, I'd have to go with the Russian just because—isn't Pollard also ethnically Jewish?For sure. A hundred percent.Yeah. No doubt.I'll tell you what, I served in prison with a mob guy named—well, I won't say it, I don't want to embarrass him—but anyway, good guy from Philadelphia. And he was at the penitentiary in Butner with Pollard, and he said Pollard was such a little mouse. Said everybody just wanted to beat the daylights out of him. So they kept him for the most part in the medical unit just for his own protection.Now he looks like Dave Letterman with a post-beard—like a [ __ ] wild man living—he looks like a crazy person. He didn't used to look like that at all. He used to look like a Williamsburg man.Okay, Nicholas Franco asks: Why do we think the majority of Jews coming from the Soviet Union are so right-wing?I don't know if that's necessarily true. But I mean, you know, look—the thing is, my take is always that refugees tend to be the ones who leave their home country because they're opposed to the ideology of their home country, which is like the anti-Castro Cubans and so on. So the Soviet Union was a socialist country. If you didn't love socialism, you left, right? What do you think?Yeah, I think that's right. Although it is my understanding that Ukrainian Jews who have left Ukraine to move to Israel are exceedingly right-wing. I've even spoken to Israeli journalists who have told me that there are so many right-wing Ukrainian Jews that have moved there just over the last twenty or twenty-five years that it's pushed the entire electorate to the right.Crazy. I mean, that is a country that has a lot of immigration, and their demographics change really radically in a relatively short amount of time as a result. We don't have that level of immigration in this country. Our demographics shift slowly.Yeah, we do. We shift slowly. And a country of only nine million people can shift very quickly when you have these huge influxes.Yeah, a hundred thousand is a lot of people in a country of nine million people.That's right.Quadruple J XYZ: Do we think that the unveiled corruption in Ukraine—unveiled my ass—it's like it's always been in plain sight—will influence Western support in any ways?It's a great question, though. We're talking about, of course, the recent scandal of the people surrounding Zelensky in this energy-bribery kind of thing, which kind of has echoes of the Hunter Biden-Burisma [ __ ]. What do you think, John?I don't think that the US is going to back away from Ukraine. Corruption goes with the territory over there. And it's not unusual. Doesn't it remind you a little bit of Hamid Karzai, where basically everyone around you is corrupt as [ __ ], but no one can prove that you personally took money? This isn't like Eric Adams, who is personally corrupt and had credible charges filed against him. Nobody really—Zelensky suddenly is rich and has this place on Lake Como, but maybe he just has a lot of good residuals from his acting career. We can't prove it, right? But like Hamid Karzai, you certainly could never prove that he personally was lining his pockets. This is kind of like President Harding or something like that.I think that's a good way to say it. And President Harding is probably the right comparison to make.Yeah, I agree with that. But you know what's painful too, Ted, is that nobody seems to really care when leaders are corrupt now.No. Nobody cares whether we're talking about domestic or foreign affairs. Nobody cares when their own side is called out. Basically there's never a thing where it's like, oh, I supported this candidate or this party, but now I've learned new information that they're a turd, so therefore I no longer support them anymore. That doesn't happen anymore. You just make excuses or you brush it off or you do whataboutism, but you don't change your mind. You don't back away. Literally nothing can make you do that. If your guy turns out to be a pedophile, you're like, eh, whatever—the other side's worse. No matter what it is. I feel like that's a change. I don't think that was true when I was a little kid. You were a little kid during Watergate. Nixon won by a landslide in 1972, but in 1974 you couldn't find anyone who admitted that they voted for him.You know what—George McGovern told me something one time that was so funny. He said that in 1972 he got 39 percent of the national vote, but he only got Massachusetts and the District of Columbia. And then in 1974, two years later, 65 percent of Americans told pollsters that they voted for McGovern.That is the total "victory has a thousand fathers and defeat is an orphan." It really is true.It is true. Yes, it is.Rebellious Rainbow Unicorn: Is the CIA more out of control now compared to pre-1995, John?Pre-1995? Absolutely, yes. No question. Pre-1975, I think it's comparable. Pre-1975 the CIA was just going around the world doing anything it pleased. They were killing world leaders. They were overthrowing governments. Half the time they weren't even bothering to inform the president what they were doing. Doping kids with LSD. Doping their own employees with LSD. And they had seriously cleaned up their act by 1995. I talk often about the so-called cull that Bill Clinton initiated in 1993 where he ordered the CIA to fire every recruited source who had a human-rights problem in his past, and fully one-third of the CIA sources were fired. Those days are gone and they're never coming back.Can you explain—like why do you think the CIA—in other words, how did the CIA get so out of control? What caused it to happen before '75? I know the Church Committee came in afterwards and there were all the scandals because of Philip Agee and all that. But when the CIA is more under control, what's the difference between that and a time like now when they're out of control? Is it leadership? What is it?It is the nature of the CIA. It's the collective mindset of the CIA to push the envelope as far as you can push until somebody in the White House pushes back or somebody on Capitol Hill pushes back. It's the culture. They called it "kingdom building" when I was there. Everybody in a position of authority at the CIA wants to build his or her own kingdom. And so you just keep pushing the boundaries of legality until somebody pushes back. And the next thing you know, they're doing anything they damn well please. There's almost zero congressional oversight. And at the White House, they just throw up their hands and say, well, what can we do? There's nothing we can do.And these days it's the lack of interest in reining them in coming from the White House, you would say?I would. And I would say the inability to rein them in on the part of the congressional oversight committees.Why are they unable?Because there are about forty employees of the Senate Intelligence Committee and about sixty employees of the House Intelligence Committee and forty thousand employees at the CIA.That's a good answer. You just can't handle it.Okay. Peru's a JFK-related question: You met or worked with David Talbot? And what do you think about his work? My impression is that he's not in good health nowadays. I'm sorry to hear that, David. Poor David.Yeah. David wrote the foreword for my third book. He's a lovely guy and one of the most highly respected contemporary historians that's out there. He had a debilitating serious stroke—his second stroke—a few months ago. And the last I heard he was unable to care for himself, unable to speak, and certainly unable to write. The poor guy.He was the editor of Salon.Yeah, he was. So my only interaction was trying to get him to run my cartoons. He ran the cartoons of four of my colleagues who were very similar to the kind of work that I did, so I thought I kind of belonged naturally in that orbit. He was nice, but obviously he didn't like my work and just didn't want to say so. And he never ran it ever. And it was always a source of frustration to me. But he's allowed to not like my work. That was my interaction with him. He was always polite, albeit a little weaselly about it. Editors.USXXXArod21, thanks for the $2. Have you seen the story about the FSB attacking Polish train tracks with C4 explosives? Was Poland right to worry about Putin and his ambitions? Or is this mind games Putin is playing? Is there a real issue? In other words, is there a real danger of Russia invading Poland here?Yeah. Yes, the Poles have reason to be worried.Really?Yeah, I do. I do believe that. Listen, the Russians are just like every other country, just like every other superpower or regional superpower. They're going to carry out operations against the countries that they believe are threats to them. And sometimes those operations are large-scale and sometimes they're small-scale, but sabotage is just a normal thing. It's almost an act of war, right? Going into a sovereign state and—Transportation infrastructure. Absolutely.But listen, even if they got caught, nobody's going to go to war over some train tracks.I got it. But I just—I don't think that Russia would invade Poland.No, no, I don't think absolutely not, because to invade Poland is to invade NATO, and then it's going to require a massive response.Destined for Nothing says: John, I saw a job posting yesterday—now removed—for a Director of Identity Intelligence at Health and Human Services—HHS. Can you shed some light on what that could mean?A Director of Identity Intelligence. The word "identity" throws me. I honestly don't know what that could mean. It's not unusual for almost every federal department to have an intelligence office. For example, there's a CIA representative from the analytics side—from the Directorate of Intelligence—at Treasury, at Commerce, at Energy. They're all over the place. Just because there is intelligence that comes in every day that needs to be shared with the leadership of those departments, right? Maybe you pick up something about threats to air travel or about some germ that's been developed somewhere, or you stole the Japanese trade-negotiation talking points and you need to share them or whatever. But "identity intelligence"—it doesn't have a meaning for me. I'm not sure what that is.All I can think of is HHS has clients. Maybe they want to know if they're US citizens or they want to know who they are. But that would normally fall under the Office of Security.Yeah. All right. So yeah, I have no clue here.Oh, Rebellious—Rebellious, I remembered. Just to say "Rebellious" instead of the whole Rebellious Rainbow Unicorn. It says "identity access" is cybersecurity.That would make sense. Thank you for that.Nicholas Franco: Do we see Trump getting the rare-earth metals from Ukraine as per that deal? It seems to me that Putin is getting all of them.Well, Putin occupies the territory where they are, and that territory is never going back to Ukraine ever.No, sir.By the way, thank you so much, Ray C 2020—longtime listener and viewer—is now a monthly supporter of "DeProgram." Thank you.Thank you.If you—so here's a buck. John, this is your question: What would it take to actually reform or dismantle the CIA?Can I get away with saying stay tuned to this channel?Yes, you can. And I know why.Yes, I'm hoping to have kind of a big announcement in the next two weeks.That'll be cool. Maybe two announcements.Maybe two announcements.All right. Capunkt t-589: Do we think that Israel has crossed the point of no return in regards to how the world sees Israelis, or does it take time and people will forget that Israel committed genocide?I think 100 percent there's no going back. I mean, I think it's so radical at this point. They've fallen off the cliff in international-opinion polling, domestic-opinion polling, and most importantly with young people—which means that these are opinions that are baked into the generations that are going to be moving forward over the next few decades. I don't see—even if Israel were to say we were wrong, we apologize, we want to help create a Palestinian state—none of these things are going to happen—but even if they did that, I think it's not going to be forgiven. It went on for so long. It was so extreme. And now it's being so reported—it's baked in. I don't see that being undone. I think Israel's kind of dead to a significant percentage of the population. What do you think?With the exception of Arab countries who do as they're told and don't give a [ __ ] about the Palestinians—the Israelis are not going to expand their list of global countries that they can rely on for support. I personally believe the Israelis are beyond the point of no return. I really do too.And just to be clear—the Arab countries you're talking about, John—I don't want to put words in your mouth ever—but we're talking about the governments of those countries, not the citizens.That is exactly right. Glad you said that.So let's talk about—while we're talking all things CIA—let's talk about the JFK assassination, which took place sixty-two years ago this coming Saturday, November 22nd. Former CIA historian Tom Percy says that he basically was doing research in a CIA safe room back in 2009 while researching Latin American policy in the CIA, and he came across a fifty-page IG—Inspector General's—report from 1978 in which—this was a period under the Carter administration during the Church Committee when the CIA was really on the hot seat for the abuses in Latin America—and they basically were laughing about the memos, laughing and bragging about fooling Congress about what Lee Harvey Oswald was up to in Mexico City before he killed JFK. It shows basically—this is kind of considered a blueprint for how you can lie to Congress as a government agency. And basically they sanitized—in other words, expunged—duplicates of files sent to the House Select Committee chief counsel. They got rid of all the key evidence. They insulted him by calling him incurious.Well, it sounds like they weren't wrong. It sounds like he sort of did give everything a twenty-, thirty-minute glance and then back to scotch on the rocks.And that's probably true. Although it's always kind of funny to me when someone engages in pernicious activity like this and then laughs at their victims for being stupid.Yes. Which I guess is what happened here.John, can you talk a little bit about this? First of all, this sounds credible to me. What was Lee Harvey Oswald up to in Mexico City before November 22nd?He was there to meet at the Soviet embassy—which turned him away—and at the Cuban embassy, which also turned him away. We only learned recently that the CIA was surveilling him in Mexico City in this most recent tranche of documents. But the CIA denied and denied and denied that they had any knowledge of Oswald being in Mexico City. That was a lie.And another lie is—and we just learned this in the latest tranche—the other lie was that the CIA had no contact with Oswald. And not only did they have contact with Oswald, but James Angleton, the deputy director for counterintelligence, ordered that the CIA recruit Oswald, even if Oswald didn't realize he had been recruited.What would that look like?You can do it as a false flag. You can do it pretending to be Russian, for example, or you can say you're a businessman looking to hire a consultant. You can tell any kind of lie you want just to set the person's mind at ease.Why did they feel a need to not reveal that? What would have been exposed by them just saying, yeah, we were surveilling him and here's what we knew?Yeah, that's just inexplicable. The CIA would have been so much better off—the country would have been so much better off—just being honest from the beginning.Or did they think it would raise additional questions?I think they probably did. But you and I just said this a couple of days ago, didn't we? That the cover-up is always worse than the crime. And so, yeah. They just didn't want to be second-guessed. Like, didn't you know he was plotting to kill the president? If so, why didn't you—or did you know and did you let it happen? Did you continue to surveil him when he came to Dallas? They just didn't want to be bothered. It sounds like—I think that's exactly what it was.And then just gloating that the chief investigator was incurious—that leads me to believe that it was an issue of gloating.And thanks for the 299 Australian dollars from Tabe J. Unfortunately, Tabe, we have already answered a question: Why has Huckabee met with Jonathan Pollard in Jerusalem? We talked about that earlier in the show, but thanks for the 299. Just hit rewind.Hey, Ted.MW Knox 186 has a good practical question: Did I ever recruit anyone without identifying myself as a CIA employee?That is a good question. The answer is yes. There was somebody I was working on who I knew had an irrational fear of the CIA. And so I said that I represented a consortium of businessmen and they were interested in this very specific information and they were willing to pay handsomely for it. So I had headquarters draw up what looked like a really official legal contract. And I offered the guy the contract. It was a consulting contract. And so he signed it. And I gave him $5,000 a month in cash in hotel rooms. And he gave me the classified information. And everybody lived happily ever after.That is a funny story.If you—so thanks for the additional dollar. What do you know, John—I assume—about the story of "The Falcon and the Snowman"?Oh, yeah. The Sean Penn movie. I like the movie. It was a great movie. It was a great book. But this is something that from the day that you're hired at the CIA they drill into you. So every new CIA employee knows the story of "The Falcon and the Snowman." So two best friends, two high-school best friends who graduated from high school. One went on to go to college. One went on to be a drug addict and a drug dealer. And the one that went to college got a job with a CIA contractor. And so he had access, of course, to classified information. The drug-addict friend ended up going down to Mexico City and approaching the Soviet embassy and saying, hey, I've got a buddy who works for the CIA, and if you give me money I'll get the information that you want from my friend. And then he used that money to buy more drugs. And it was all fine and good until they got caught. And one cooperated—or both cooperated—actually I'm going to Google it now 'cause I can't remember if it was one or both that cooperated—but they both ended up with long prison sentences.I'm going to look it up right now while you're hearing that. Go ahead.Yeah, it was Christopher Boyce who was played by Timothy Hutton. His dad got him a job at the CIA. And then, yeah—his friend finally admitted, hey, all the questions that I ask you I've been telling the Soviet embassy in Mexico City. He suggested that they run off to Costa Rica where he had secretly bought a house instead. Boyce turned himself in.Yeah, the reason they call them "The Falcon and the Snowman" is the Timothy Hutton character raised falcons, and "Snowman" was cocaine.Yeah.Sean Pat 6882: Is the fear of the CIA ever irrational?I'd say no.No. Fear of government is never irrational.I love this question.Rodie Bang Bang: What do we think about this new commercial that the Democrats put out telling American soldiers that they don't have to follow unlawful orders? I saw this. Dangerous, if I say so myself, he or she says.You know, the Democrats have this obsession that Donald Trump is going to try to seize power and refuse to leave the White House at the end of his term. And Trump loves trolling them on issues like this.Yeah, so the Democrats—last week Democrats have some cause to be concerned about that, in fairness, maybe just a little. I think Trump's just enjoying himself watching the Democrats lose their minds over this.So several—more than several, half a dozen—Democratic leaders last week came out with this nicely produced advertisement urging members of the military to defy illegal orders, unlawful orders—that if Trump says he's not leaving, he's going to declare himself dictator, whatever.I'm wondering what that all—I took that also as having to do with the ICE actions on the streets and the National Guard being sent to various American cities, like there in Charlotte. That would be more immediate.I didn't see it that way. That would be a little bit scarier.So it's so impossible, right? I've never understood how members of the military reconcile this innate contradiction—which you and I have talked about before—between being told that you have to follow orders unquestioningly from your commanding officer, and at the same time you shouldn't, and in fact you're legally prohibited from following unlawful orders. Those two directives seem to me like they're going to come into conflict. And it's impossible for a service person to know what to do in a My Lai-type situation. You know what's morally right.Yeah. But I mean, what do you really truly—I feel like it's an impossible situation. I wouldn't want to be in a situation like this. It's like at the very end of his first term when Trump walked out into that demonstration in front of St. John's Church across the street from the White House and asked the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, why don't you just shoot them? And he's like, serious? I have to explain to you why we can't just go out and shoot unarmed civilians in the streets in front of the White House? Insane.So, I mean, I don't know. Is it dangerous to have a political party say, hey, you don't have to necessarily follow the orders that you get when you're in the armed services?It's a statement of fact. You don't necessarily.It could be dangerous. Yes. And I think the Democrats are jumping the gun on this. I really do. I wish that they'd had less balls here and more balls in the showdown over the shutdown—because that one where they were afraid of [ __ ] the airline lobby. That's what this was about.Oh, God.Let me read an ad, John. Looking for smarter ways to browse and enjoy your favorite content without ads? Get the Perplexity Pro bundle with Rumble Premium for just $19.99 a month when you sign up before December 31st. Normally it's a $29.99 value. With Rumble Premium you'll get an ad-free viewing experience across all your devices and access to exclusive premium content—no interruptions, just the videos and streams you love anytime, anywhere. Plus Perplexity Pro boosts your productivity with unlimited research, unlimited uploads, exclusive member perks, and access to the latest and most advanced AI models for faster, smarter answers every day. Save over 30 percent on this powerful bundle. Head to rumble.com/premium before December 31st to sign up and unlock your premium experience.Thank you. By the way, we are on the front page of Rumble right now, even as we speak. So that's fun and exciting. And thank you very much for the $10 donation from Village Idiot TV. Much appreciated.That's wonderful. Thank you.Okay, so let's—shall we talk about—we have good timing here today. Sometimes we run out of time, but okay. So Donald Trump and Zohran Mamdani, the mayor-elect of New York City who takes office in about six weeks, are going to meet at the White House in the Oval Office tomorrow.Ted, I thought you were joking when you sent this to me. I had to actually look it up.No, it's true. Apparently this is a tradition for the new mayor of New York City. From what we've heard, Mamdani has requested the meeting. Trump agreed.All right, so I have many questions. There's the meta question of what does it say? How many times do the American people have to sit through an election where the two adversaries repeatedly say the other is the devil himself—he's evil, he hangs out with Satan, he's going to destroy America—and then the other one is scum, horrible communist, he's going to send everyone to gulags—and then the election's over and it's like, John's not so bad, Ted's okay, and then oh, I love you, let's work together? I know that's the tradition and it works—it worked historically—but I just feel like in a time of social media and everything, it's hard going forward to take anything that any politician ever says seriously, because you know that they're likely going to end up in this place, right?Yeah. Like the guy who can't pronounce his name—the Christides dude.John Katsimatidis.He's like, oh, I want the best now for Mamdani. Of course I'm not going anywhere—St. Petersburg. He's going to move to St. Petersburg because he can never live in a socialist city. And now he's like, ah, Mamdani's not so bad.So first of all, is it going to be maybe not a love-in but will it be a like-in tomorrow? Or will it be sort of Vance versus Zelensky? What's going to happen?Yeah, I think it is going to be a like-in. By most accounts—unless your name is Volodymyr Zelensky—Trump treats people with respect when they visit him in the White House. And I think that they're going to make public statements in the end about areas in which they can cooperate. I think Mamdani is going to say, look, we're not trying to take over the grocery stores. I appointed the same police commissioner that Mayor Adams appointed—she's staying on in the job.I think she's from a really rich family too.Oh, I didn't know that.Oh yeah. No, she's one of the famous Tisch—like Lawrence Tisch.Oh boy. Oh boy.Yeah. All right. I don't know why she'd want to be the head of the NYPD, but why just sit home and count your money?But I think that's what we're going to see. I think this is going to be a like-in. They'll agree to disagree like gentlemen. And Mamdani is no threat to Trump. And Trump really can't do much to hurt Mamdani, especially when Mamdani is surrounding himself with people from the Adams administration.Yeah, he is. And also Mamdani has been very canny about making nice with Governor Hochul—which is the most important connection that he can possibly have. Andrew Cuomo never got along with Mayor de Blasio. That was a problem for de Blasio.Although these days de Blasio is looking good. He really is. He's got a new girlfriend. He's got a TV gig. Things are good for him. And not to mention his mayoralty turns out—compared to Adams?Oh my God.Yeah, I just heard a story—just for example, this is a very local New York City story—but when he became mayor he quietly—and never bragged about this—ordered the NYPD to completely dig into all the backlog of rape kits and process them all and get completely caught up. And now the Adams administration immediately fell behind and basically we're right back where we started. But that was an example of something de Blasio took seriously and cared about.My best friend lives in New York all of his life on the Lower East Side. His one and only child—his daughter—just graduated from high school, but when she was a freshman, three or four years ago, she was walking home from school like she did every day, walking up First Avenue, and a homeless guy walked up to her and punched her in the face as hard as he could—almost knocked her out—and then just walked away. And when my friend called the cops, the cops are like, what do you want us to do about it? This kind of thing happens.That happened to me. I was walking out of the Chambers Street subway station years ago, and a homeless guy coming down the stairs just casually slugged me in the face—broke my glasses. I'm lucky the glass didn't go into my eyes. And it was just like he just left. And it's the same sort of—didn't even bother to go to the cops because it's true: what do you want them to do? Even if they caught the [ __ ], he's not going to stay in prison. He's going to be out on the street.The point I wanted to make was that at least under Adams there was no real move to make the streets any safer. There are these catastrophes happening in subway stations—people being beaten, raped, mugged, shoved in front of trains. It happens practically every week or two. This guy was a police captain. I thought he was supposed to be the law-and-order candidate. Instead he was just a bozo.Yeah. By the way, speaking of which—remember that really crazy story in New York, I think this happened in Coney Island at the end of the line in Brooklyn, where a lady was set on fire—a homeless lady—by some degenerate? Well, a similar event just happened yesterday in Chicago where someone was set on fire, and the suspect was apprehended. I was wondering—what do you think about the fact that the Chicago police have decided to charge him with terrorism? The arsonist.Oh God. We've talked about this in the past. Terrorism is inflicting terror on a population for a political purpose.Yeah. So this is not terrorism.No, it's not.Let's go through some comments.Still 2082: ICE is literally not evil. They are literally not doing evil. It is literally not evil to enforce immigration laws. Democrats are evil for committing sedition and treason with that video.I appreciate the comment. And here's the thing: I agree 100 percent that a country has the duty and the right to enforce its laws, and illegal immigration is illegal. The thing is how you enforce the law matters. Like if a cop stops you for speeding, he can't just shoot you—"Well, he was enforcing the law." It's like, okay, but he wasn't enforcing the law the right way. ICE is not enforcing the law the right way. They're ethnically profiling. And we know they're ethnically profiling because they're grabbing people who are US citizens—including Native Americans who happen to have brown skin. Are being arrested and detained—in one case deported to Mexico.Yeah. And also there's prosecutorial discretion, right? Obviously a cop should pull over the dude going 95 before he pulls over the guy going 58. And again, ICE is not doing that. ICE is not going after convicted rapists who are illegal immigrants. They're going after sort of anyone and everyone, and it seems almost like the low-hanging fruit is people dropping their kids off at school and stuff. It's wrong.Question for both of us: Do we consume media in your other languages—like music, movies, TV, etc.?I absolutely do. And I listen to French music. I even have this app on my phone called ERTFLIX—ERT is Greek television. This ERTFLIX has like every channel in Greece, and you can watch movies and concerts and soap operas and sports events. I watch it every single day. I even have TV for France, for Greece. There's a TV station in Patras—Greece's third city on the west coast—that has its own app. I watch Patras TV. And then the Church of Greece has its own app, its own TV station. So I just watch church on TV on Sunday mornings. I stopped going to church, I don't know, a year ago.I will want to ask you about the not going to church, but let's try to get through some more questions.Frasmitas, request for you, John: Please recount one of your best Alec Baldwin stories for us when time permits. I haven't heard a single Alec Baldwin story since the Sputnik-Assange days and then his film "Rust."I have an Alec story too, but go ahead.Alec Baldwin and I hate each other. And hate each other to the point where we can't be in the same room together. And the story—we met once. A friend of mine wanted to write a play about my trial or the case leading up to trial, and he wanted to do it off-Broadway. And Alec was interested in playing me. And so we met for lunch one day in New York. And my friend—my friend's an Academy Award-winning writer, screenwriter. So he asked me to tell him these stories. I'm telling these stories. Thirty minutes into it, Alec says, I think you're full of [ __ ]. And I said, excuse me? And he says, I think you're full of [ __ ]. I think you're just making all this [ __ ] up. And I said, I've been called a lot of things in my life, but liar is not one of them. He goes, [ __ ] you. I said, [ __ ] you, Baldwin. And I was so angry. I got up and I walked out of the restaurant, and my friend is like, guys, please—no, please, please. So I was so mad I walked all the way back to Penn Station. I got on the train and I came home.So about six months later I had this idea for a TV series. I had written a pilot—and this I do as a hobby; I've written seven of them in the last fourteen years and I've actually sold all seven; one made it to pilot. So we made this pitch at Fox, and Fox is like, nah, we're not really interested—it's moderately interesting but it's not for us. So our next pitch meeting was at AMC. And before we went in, my buddy said, you know, we can guarantee a sale to AMC if we can attach an A-list star. And I said, oh, please don't. He said, please. He is an Academy Award winner. He's an Emmy Award winner. So we called him. We went to Soho House—they have breakout rooms there. We called him, and my friend said, uh, Alec, I'm here with Kiriakou—and Baldwin says, what's that [ __ ] want? And I said, yeah, nice to talk to you too again, Alec. And then he said, well, John's got an idea for a show. And I told him the idea for the show. And he says, actually, that is a pretty good idea. Go ahead and attach me. So we attached him. We sold it to AMC the very next day.And six weeks later I called my attorney and I said, I haven't heard anything from AMC's business-affairs office. I have no idea if my deal's been negotiated. He said, you know, I forgot all about that. Let me call over there. He calls over to AMC, and AMC says, we dropped that show. And my attorney says, why? 'Cause Alec Baldwin quit to take a deal with HBO. So I called him back and I said, [ __ ] you, Baldwin. Don't ever call me again. And I hung up. That was the last time we spoke.It sounds like this relationship—this friendship—might be beyond redemption, John. Just saying.Yeah, no. Then when he got arrested for shooting that assistant director or whatever she was on the movie "Rust," my buddy called and said, hey, you know, it looks like Alec may be going to prison. You might want to give him a ring and just try to—and I said, [ __ ] him. I hope he rots in prison.OMG. Thanks for the five bucks, Angela. Thank you much. Appreciate it.Quick last question. Hype show. Will Mamdani really imprison B.B. if he comes to New York, or is that just talk?I think it's real. And it should be.Yeah. Yes.Everyone, thanks so much for joining us. This is the "DeProgram" show with me, Ted Rall, and John Kiriakou. We are here Monday through Friday at 9 a.m. Eastern Time, which means we will be back tomorrow—Friday—at 9 a.m. We will see you then. Please stay tuned for the TMI show with me and Manila Chan coming right up after this. We much appreciate you. And oh, also DMZ America podcast—Scott Stantis and I will be interviewing editorial cartoonist Steve Kelley, who's a conservative. That's at 11 a.m. Eastern Time this morning.Bye, John. See you tomorrow.Bye-bye, everybody.